Kaushal Kafle

Room 101A, McGlothlin Street Hall, Williamsburg, VA-23187 kkafle@wm.edu | +1 (757) 472-8662 | www.kaushalkafle.com

BIO

I am a PhD student in the Department of Computer Science at William & Mary with an expected graduation in Spring 2024. My advisor is Prof. <u>Adwait Nadkarni</u>. I am the lead graduate student at *Secure Platforms Lab (SPL)*, where I currently lead 5 other graduate and 2 undergraduate students. My research analyzes the security and/or privacy of emergent, evolving systems and their implications on the end users. My work on analyzing the security of smart home platforms received the *best paper award* at CODASPY'19, and has been featured in various news outlets. My work on understanding the privacy postures of election campaign websites received the *best poster award* at CCI Symposium'23.

EDUCATION

William & Mary, Williamsburg, USA

August 2017 - Present

PhD in Computer Science Advisor: Dr. Adwait Nadkarni Expected graduation: March, 2024

Pulchowk Campus, Tribhuvan University

Nov 2011 - Nov 2015

BE in Computer Engineering

PUBLICATIONS

Conference Papers

- [1] **Kaushal Kafle**, Prianka Mandal, Kapil Singh, Benjamin Andow, and Adwait Nadkarni, "Understanding the Privacy Practices of Political Campaigns: A Perspective from the 2020 US Election Websites", In *Proceedings of the 45th IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy (IEEE S&P)*, CA, USA, 2024. *To appear* [PDF]
- [2] Xin Jin*, Sunil Manandhar*, **Kaushal Kafle**, Zhiqiang Lin, and Adwait Nadkarni. "Understanding IoT Security from a Market-Scale Perspective". In *Proceedings of the 29th ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS)*, Los Angeles, CA, USA, Nov 2022. *Co-first Authors. [PDF]
- [3] Sunil Manandhar, **Kaushal Kafle**, Benjamin Andow, Kapil Singh, and Adwait Nadkarni, "Smart Home Privacy Policies Demystified: A Study of Availability, Content, and Coverage". In *Proceedings of the 31st USENIX Security Symposium (USENIX)*, Boston, MA, USA, 2022. [PDF]
- [4] Amit Seal Ami, Nathan Cooper, **Kaushal Kafle**, Kevin Moran, Denys Poshyvanyk, and Adwait Nadkarni, "Why Crypto-detectors Fail: A Systematic Evaluation of Cryptographic Misuse Detection Techniques," in *Proceedings of the 43rd IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy (IEEE S&P)*, 2022. [PDF]
- [5] Sunil Manandhar, Kevin Moran, **Kaushal Kafle**, Ruhao Tang, Denys Poshyvanyk, and Adwait Nadkarni. "Towards a Natural Perspective of Smart Homes for Practical Security and Safety Analyses." In *Proceedings of the 41st IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy (S&P)*, San Francisco, CA, USA, May 2020. [PDF]
- [6] **Kaushal Kafle**, Kevin Moran, Sunil Manandhar, Adwait Nadkarni, and Denys Poshyvanyk. "A Study of Data Store-based Home Automation." In *Proceedings of the 9th ACM Conference on Data and Application Security and Privacy (CODASPY)*. Dallas, TX, USA, March 2019. **Best Paper Award** [PDF] [press coverage]
- [7] Richard Bonett, **Kaushal Kafle**, Kevin Moran, Adwait Nadkarni, and Denys Poshyvanyk. "Discovering Flaws in Security-Focused Static Analysis Tools for Android using Systematic Mutation." In *Proceedings of the 27th USENIX Security Symposium. Baltimore*, MD, USA, Aug 2018. [Source code] [PDF]

Journal Papers	
----------------	--

- [8] Amit Seal Ami, **Kaushal Kafle**, Kevin Moran, Adwait Nadkarni, and Denys Poshyvanyk. "Systematic Mutation-based Evaluation of the Soundness of Security-focused Android Static Analysis Techniques". In *ACM Transactions on Security & Privacy (TOPS)*, 2021. [PDF]
- [9] **Kaushal Kafle**, Kevin Moran, Sunil Manandhar, Adwait Nadkarni, and Denys Poshyvanyk. "Security in Centralized Data Store-based Home Automation Platforms- A Systematic Analysis of Nest and Hue." In *ACM Transactions on Cyber-Physical Systems (TCPS)*, 2020. [PDF]

Tool Demo Papers

- [10] Prianka Mandal, Sunil Manandhar, **Kaushal Kafle**, Kevin Moran, Denys Poshyvanyk, and Adwait Nadkarni. "Helion: Enabling Natural Testing of Smart Homes". In Proceedings of the ACM Joint European Software Engineering Conference and Symposium on the Foundations of Software Engineering (ESEC/FSE), Demonstration Track, Dec 2023. [PDF]
- [11] Amit Seal Ami, Syed Yusuf Ahmed, Radowan Mahmud Redoy, Nathan Cooper, **Kaushal Kafle**, Kevin Moran, Denys Poshyvanyk, and Adwait Nadkarni. "MASC: A Tool for Mutation-based Evaluation of Static Crypto-API Misuse Detectors". In *Proceedings of the ACM Joint European Software Engineering Conference and Symposium on the Foundations of Software Engineering (ESEC/FSE), Demonstration Track, Dec 2023. [PDF]*
- [12] Amit Seal Ami, **Kaushal Kafle**, Kevin Moran, Adwait Nadkarni, and Denys Poshyvanyk. "Demo: Mutation-based Evaluation of Security-focused Static Analysis Tools for Android." In *Proceedings of the 43rd IEEE/ACM International Conference on Software Engineering (ICSE'21), Formal Tool Demonstration*, May 2021, [PDF]

Posters

- [13] "Security and Privacy in the Smart Home Ecosystem", at the *Annual Virginia Academy of Science, Engineering and Medicine (VASEM) Summit*, Richmond, VA Oct 2023 [PDF]
- [14] "Expanding Computer Science Learning Opportunities in K-12 Instruction in Virginia Schools", at the *Annual Virginia Academy of Science, Engineering and Medicine (VASEM) Summit*, Richmond, VA Oct 2023 [PDF]
- [15] "Understanding the Privacy Practices of Political Campaigns", at the *CCI Symposium* '23, Richmond, VA April 2023 *Best Poster Award* [PDF]
- [16] "Smart Home Privacy Demystified", at the CCI Symposium 2022, Richmond, VA April 2022 [PDF]
- [17] "A Study of Data Store-based Home Automation", at ACM CODASPY'19, Dallas, TX March 2019 [PDF]

CONTRIBUTION IN AWARDED GRANT

- [1] NSF Grant CNS 2132281
 - a. Title: "Enabling Data-Driven Security and Safety Analyses for Cyber-Physical Systems"
 - b. PI: Adwait Nadkarni, Kevin Moran, Co-Pi: Denys Poshyvanyk, Contributor: Kaushal Kafle
 - c. Award amount: \$799,839

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Graduate Research Assistant

Jan 2018 – Present

Secure Platforms Lab (SPL)

Department of Computer Science, William & Mary

Research Overview: As a research assistant to Prof. Adwait Nadkarni at SPL, I have worked primarily in the analysis of security and/or privacy of emergent, evolving systems such as IoT systems, election campaigning platforms and security analysis tools.

Projects and Artifacts:

- 1. **Polityzer**, IEEE S&P'24 Source Code: https://github.com/polityzer
- 2. Security of Centralized Home Automation, Best Paper, ACM CODASPY'19 Press Coverage: https://kaushalkafle.com/publications#press
- 3. IoTSpotter, ACM CCS'22 Source Code: https://github.com/Secure-Platforms-Lab-W-M/IoTSpotter
- 4. Smart Home Privacy Policies Demystified, USENIX'22 Data: https://github.com/Secure-Platforms-Lab-W-M/smart-home-privacy-policies
- 5. Helion, IEEE S&P'20 Source Code: https://github.com/Secure-Platforms-Lab-W-M/Helion-on-Home-Assistant#helion
- 6. **HomeEndorser**, *under submission*: A security framework for securing automations in smart home platforms.
- 7. Mutation-based Soundness Evaluation (MUSE), USENIX'18 Source Code: https://secure-platforms-labw-m.github.io/muse/
- 8. Mutation Analysis for evaluating Static Crypto-API misuse detectors (MASC), IEEE S&P'22 Source Code: https://github.com/Secure-Platforms-Lab-W-M/masc-artifact

Lead Graduate Student June 2022 – Present

Secure Platforms Lab (SPL)

Department of Computer Science, William & Mary

Responsibilities:

- Provided individual research mentorship and support to other graduate/undergraduate students
- Helped in fostering a good working environment among lab students
- Organized and led student-run weekly meetings
- Led the daily operational activities of the lab

INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE

Virginia Department of Education, Richmond, VA May 2023 – Aug 2023

Commonwealth of Virginia Engineering and Science (COVES) Policy Fellow

Mentor: Keisha Tennessee, Virginia Computer Science Coordinator

Responsibilities:

- Support the strategic planning in VA to expand capacity, access, and participation in K-12 Computer Science Education
- Dataset collection, analysis and providing data-based recommendations

Mojo Vision, Tectus Corp., Saratoga, CA Sep 2022 – Nov 2022

Graduate Research Intern Mentor: Dr. Michael Grace

Responsibilities:

- Investigate the security and privacy implications of AR Contact Lens
- Design a new security framework for AR Contact Lens

IBM Research, Yorktown Heights, NY May 2022 – Aug 2022

Graduate Research Intern Mentor: Dr. Kapil Singh

Responsibilities:

• Investigate the feasibility of mapping specific privacy and data policies to the software code behavior

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Guest Lecturer, William & Mary

1. Guest Lecture on "Practical Integrity in the Smart Home", in Concepts of Computer Security – CSCI 667 (Graduate-level course) – Spring 2022

- 2. Guest Lecture on "Ramifications of SSL Issues in Mobile Apps for the Smart Home", in Mobile Application Security CSCI 445 (Undergraduate-level course) Fall 2021 Online (over zoom)
- 3. Guest Lecture on "Securing a Smart Home", in IoT Security and Safety CSCI 680 (Graduate-level course) Spring 2021 Online (over zoom)

Teaching Assistant, William & Mary

Aug 2017 – May 2019

- 4. Taught labs and graded assignments in *Computational Problem Solving* CSCI 141 (133 Students)
- 5. Taught labs and graded assignments in *Programming for Data Science* CSCI 140 (93 Students)
- 6. Graded assignments in *Mobile App Security* CSCI 520 Spring 2018 (20 Students), Fall 2018 (12 Students)

CONFERENCE PRESENTATIONS, INVITED TALKS AND OUTREACH

Conference Presentations

- 1. "A Study of Data-store Based Home Automation" at the 9th ACM CODASPY, Dallas, TX March 2019
- 2. "A Study of Data-store Based Home Automation" at the 18th Graduate Research Symposium, William & Mary, Williamsburg March 2019
- 3. "Discovering Flaws in Security-Focused Static Analysis Tools for Android using Systematic Mutation" at the 27th USENIX Security Symposium, Baltimore August 2018

Invited Talks and Outreach

- 4. "Guest Post: A PhD Student's Experience at the LiSPI Workshop", Leadership in Science Policy Institute (LiSPI) workshop, invited by Computing Research Association (CRA), Washington DC Nov 2023 [Link]
- 5. "Understanding the Security of Smart Home Platforms", as part of the Emerging Scholar Series, Public Scholarship Initiative, Williamsburg Regional Library March 2022
- 6. "How hackable is your home?", invited as an expert on smart home security in Which? Investigates podcast (Episode Link) October 2021
- 7. "The Security of Smart Home Platforms", Research talk at the **Journal Club**, William & Mary, Williamsburg September 2019
- 8. "Enabling Safe and Secure Home Automation: Problems, Best Practices and Future Opportunities", William & Mary Developer Outreach to Williamsburg Developers Group, Williamsburg, VA, July 2019
- 9. Outreach to High School Students, invited by Advanced Technology Center, V. Beach, VA April 2019
- 10. "Hacking Your Smart Home" podcast, invited to discuss my work on smart home security by News Radio WINA December 2018

AWARDS & HONORS

- 1. Commonwealth of Virginia Engineering & Science (COVES) Policy Fellow, Selected by Virginia Academy of Science, Engineering and Medicine (VASEM), Host office Virginia Department of Education, 2023
- 2. Best Poster Award, CCI Symposium 2023, Richmond, VA, USA April 2023
- 3. Best Paper Award, ACM CODASPY, Dallas, TX, USA March 2019
- 4. Graduate Studies Advisory Board (GSAB) Research Grant, William & Mary Fall 2021
- 5. International Student Opportunity Award, William & Mary Spring 2020, Spring 2021
- 6. Travel Award USENIX Security Symposium 2018, Computing Research Association (CRA) 2023

PROFESSIONAL SERVICE

- 1. Conference Program Committee Member
 - a. USENIX Security Symposium (USENIX) Artifact Evaluation Committee 2021, 2022, 2023
 - b. Annual Computer Security Applications Conference (ACSAC) Artifact Evaluation Committee 2023
- 2. Conference External Reviewer
 - a. Top-tier conferences NDSS (2020, 2021, 2022, 2023), USENIX (2019, 2021)
 - b. Other conferences ACSAC (2022, 2023), ICISS (2019, 2022, 2023), ACNS (2022, 2023, 2024)